number five asks draw the correct form
of the resonance hybrid given the
following resonance structures so let's
take a look at what we've got here we
have an oxyanion right there so we have
an O minus right there and then how are
we getting to each of these resonance
structures we can take this negative
charge and form a CO Pi Bond right there
if we then take this Pi Bond and push
that up into the carbon atom to get that
next annion right there so as we can see
we've got the pie Bond there and then we
have the new location for the anion so
we've shifted that o minus over to a c
minus now let's take that and let's put
that right there we can make another
piie Bond there if we take this piie
Bond and we push it up onto that carbon
so now we have a pi Bond here and we
have a new location for the carbanion
then to get to that fourth resonance
structure we are going to put that right
here